TOHO CORPORATION
Some mornings, I wake up crying
without knowing why.
That's when everything happens
now and again.
Whatever that dream was I had,
I can never remember it.
- But...
the only thing that
does last when I wake up
is a sense of loss,
which lingers for a long time afterwards.
I'm always searching for something
or someone.
Mitsuha: I've been consumed by this feeling...
ever since that day.
Taki: The day... a star fell.
It was almost like...
-like seeing something out of a dream.
Nothing more or less...
- than a breathtaking view.
Ah, if only our voices speak at night
could ever reach the very
edge of this world
and of time
instead of fading into air and dust.
Then what will the words, could it ever be
farthest words from "probably"?
Let's make a promise that will never fade.
Let's say it together on
the count of three, oh.
Ah, I'm told that some part of
every wish will be heard,
but lately I've lost sight of
the truth in those words.
I can't even remember when
I gave up believing.
What could have been the reason?
Ah, the very moment that the rain will stop
in the place rainbow born and dies.
And where the end of this life lies,
I've always been insisting there was
something that I've longing for.
One day we'll reach to emotions
unexplored, unprecedented.
We'll high-five love we've yet to
discover and give a kiss to time.
The five dimensions keeps on teasing me,
but I will keep on looking at you, dear.
Let's make a sign for when we
say "nice to meet you" again.
I'm on my way to you,
chasing after your name.
Taki...
Taki.
Taki!
Don't you remember?
My name is...
Mitsuha!
Sis, what are you... doing?
Whoa, they're so realistic-feeling...
"Sis"?
Me?
Are you still asleep?
Breakfast time, hurry up!
Huh?
Wha-?
WHAAAT?!
Do you wanna have any of
last night's fish, grandma?
You can eat it.
- Mornin'!
Lazy butt, you're so slow!
I'll fix breakfast tomorrow.
Oh, that's a lot...
-Oh, well.
- You're back to normal today.
- Huh?
- You were so crazy yesterday.
- What do you mean, "crazy"?
-Attention, citizens of Itomori.
Good morning!
This is an official announcement
from Itomori Town Hall.
It is in regards to the mayoral election.
The election will be held
on the 20th of next month.
The election committee would
like to remind everyone tha-
"Comet to pass by in a month:
Visible to the naked eye"
A comet that comes only
once every 1,200 years
will finally be headed our way in a month.
The comet will be visible to the naked eye for
several days once it approaches the Earth...
Just make up with him already, okay?
- That's an adult matter.
- According to JAXA's spokesperson, they're preparing for the celestial show of the millennium.
"Position of Comet Tiamat"
"Closest on October 4th"
- We're leaving!
Yotsuha: I can't wait 'til the festival!
It's gonna be so much fun!
Study hard, sis!
Ah!
Mitsuha!
Good mornin', Saya! Mornin', Teshi!
- Mornin'!
- Come on, would you get off already?
- What for, meanie?
- 'Cause you're heavy.
- Hey, that's rude!
- Y'know, I gotta say. You two make a great couple.
- No, we don't!
Oh, I see you actually
bothered to do your hair today.
-Wait, what?
-Oh, yeah. What happened?
Did your grandma exorcise all your demons?
- Exorcise?
- Somethin' totally possessed your body!
Would you just give it a rest
with all this occult nonsense?
- Mitsuha's gotta be feelin'
stressed enough as it is, right?
- What are you guys talking about?
Are you feelin' okay?
And above all, restoring the town's fiscal health
so we can continue our revitalization project.
It's only when all these things are achieved
that we can create a safe and secure community.
- As the incumbent, my administration...
- Miyamizu's gonna get another term anyway.
I hear he's been dullin' out the pork.
Just between us.
- Hey, Miyamizu.
- Mornin'.
Looks like the mayor and the
contractor's kid are pretty cozy, too.
-To improve the quality of
life of each and every resident.
- Mitsuha!
- [Gasp]
Stand up straight when you're walking!
Oh, he's tough on his family.
Well, that's the mayor for ya.
- Awkward.
- Sucks to be her.
Mitsuha!
In front of everyone.
"Who are you?"
"Tasokare" [Twilight]
"Two light." That's the
origin of the word twilight.
I'm sure everyone here knows that word.
It's dusk, a time when
it's neither day nor night.
When the border between worlds blur,
and one might encounter
something not human.
Another older term for it is dusk light.
Some people also call it "golden hour".
"Karetaso/Kawatare = Who is that?"
-What about "magic hour"?
It's something my grandma says.
-Well, golden hour and magic
hour are technically the same,
but it's a term that
mostly photographers use.
"Who are you?"
- Well, she does take a lot of pictures.
- [CLASS Laughing]
-Okay, next...
- Miyamizu!
- Uh, yes?
Well, I can see that you
remember your own name today.
[Laughing]
Sayaka: You... don't remember?
Mitsuha: Uh-uh...
Well, believe it or not, you forgot where
your own desk and locker were yesterday.
Plus, you had the worst case of bedhead,
and you didn't have your ribbon on, either!
What?! No way!
Yeah, it was like you
had amnesia or somethin'.
Now that you mention it, I do feel like
I've been havin' weird dreams lately.
Like a dream about someone else's life?
It's all so fuzzy.
Wait a sec, I've got it...
It's memories from a previous life,
or maybe your subconscious linked to the
Everett interpretation of the multiverse!
Keep your full mouth shut!
Wait a minute! Teshi, don't tell me you
were the one who wrote in my noteboo... k.
Forget it.
But you really were actin' just a
little funny yesterday, Mitsuha.
You been feelin' okay?
That's what's weird. I feel fine.
Maybe it's from stress. You know, you've
got that ritual comin' up soon, don'tcha?
Ugh, don't remind me!
I can't stand this place anymore!
It's too small and town-ey.
I wanna graduate already and
go to Tokyo as soon as I can!
-Can't say I blame you. There really
is nothin' at all in this town.
-There's only one train that stops here every two
hours -and all the stores close at nine o' clock.
No bookstores, no dentists,
"Mother's" "Cat's Eye Pub"
but two cocktail lounges
for whatever reason.
- No jobs in town.
- No one date-able.
Even the days are too short.
You know what?!
- No, what?
Forget that stuff.
Why don't we go to a café?
- A café?
- Really?
- Where?!
Hello, kids!
- Hi, there!
- Evenin', ma'am!
- How is this a café?
- Like this town's got a café.
Mitsuha just went straight home.
- Things have gotta be really
rough for her right now.
- She's on center stage and all.
Yeah...
- Hey, Teshi...
- Hm?
What are you gonna do after
you graduate high school?
Where'd that come from?
You talkin' about the future?
Mh-hm.
I dunno. I think I'll probably just end up
livin' in this town, y'know. Same as ever.
I wanna do what you're doin'.
It's still too soon for you to
try, Yotsuha.
Listen to the thread's voice.
When you twine it round and round like this, feelings
will start flowing between you and the thread.
- It's not like threads talk...
- She's telling you to focus.
Etched within our braided cords is a
thousand years' worth of Itomori's history.
Listen. Somethin' happened
two hundred years ago...
Here she goes.
The bathroom of sandal maker Mayugoro Yamazaki
caught on fire and this whole area burned down.
The shrine and old
documents were destroyed.
- This is known as...
- Mayugoro's Great Fire.
They named the fire after him?!
I feel bad for Mayugoro.
The meaning behind our festivals
was lost because of that.
Only the surface was left.
But even if those words are
gone, those words shouldn't fade.
That's the Miyamizu shrine's duty.
Our important task.
Ugh...
Despite all that, that son-in-law of mine!
Abandoning the Shinto priesthood and leaving
this house were bad enough, but politics?!
Oh, he's hopeless!
-Have another, mister foreman.
- I'll be counting on your
help again for this election.
- Leave it to me.
You'll get the votes from the
Kadoiri and Sakagami Districts, guaranteed.
- How's the datin' scene?
- It ain't easy, that's for sure.
- Smells like corruption in there.
- What are you talkin' about?
- We're gonna need two
or three more bottles.
- Yes, dear.
Katsuhiko, you're gonna help
out at the site this weekend.
- We'll be usin' explosives,
so you better study up.
- Grngh.
What was that?!
Got it!
Guess we both can't stand things here.
Is that Yotsuha? She's all grown up.
They're lookers, alright.
Just like their mother.
- Heya!
- Hey.
World's oldest kind of sake,
but chewin' on rice, spittin' it out, and then
lettin' it ferment naturally, it becomes alcohol.
Kuchikamizake.
Do the gods really appreciate that.
The way it's ma-
Yeah, of course they do!
Hey, check it out. It's Miyamizu.
-Ugh! I'd never do that!
-And in front of everybody!
Embarrassing, right?
You should try to cheer up, sis.
Who cares if a few of the kids
from your school saw that?
It must be nice for you
not being a teenager.
Hey, I know! You should just sell
Kuchikamizake and move to Tokyo!
I bet you could sell it with all sorts of
stuff like photos and making-of videos.
Oh, and then you can call it "Shrine
Maiden's Sake"! You'll make buttloads!
"Shrine Maiden's Sake"
I can't! There are liquor laws!
That's what you have a problem with?
I hate this town! I hate this life, too!
Please make me a handsome
Tokyo boy in my next life!
Yotsuha: What a jackass.
Ow...
Where...?
Huh?
Hmm?
Something's... there...
Aaaah!
Eh!
Taki's Father: Taki, you up?
It was your turn to cook breakfast,
wasn't it? Did you sleep in?
I'm sorry.
Ugh, I'm heading out.
- Finish the miso.
- Uh, okay...
Make sure you go to school,
even if you're late. Seeya.
H-have a nice day.
What a strange dream...
[Gasp]
"From Tsukasa: Run, you're late!"
Huh? It's from "Tsukasa"?
Who's that? Hrm.
Uhhh...
I gotta go pee.
Way too real...
"Shinjuku Station"
I'm in Tokyo!
"Jingu High School"
- Where did you get this?
- Daikanyama.
Guess who's opening at our next gig?
- W-wait wait, we have a gig?
- Hey, let's skip club stuff
today and catch a movie.
Uh...
Taaaki!
Can't believe you got in at noon.
Come on, let's grab lunch!
You ignored my text, too!
- Mr. Tsukasa.
- "Mister"? You don't have to go that far.
- You got lost?
- Yeah.
Wait a second. How'd you wind up
getting lost on the way to school?
Uh...
-Well, a girl-
-A girl?
A gal-
- Hm?
I mean...
- Huh?!
A guy...
- [Nod]
Y'know, guys just wanna have fun. Every day's a
festival when you're living in Tokyo... as a guy.
Hey, you... sound funny.
-And where's your lunch?
- Seriously?
- What is up with you?
- We could share somethin'.
- Let's make a croquette-egg sandwich.
-Yes! Hahahaha!
Ah...
Thank you!
- Wanna hit the café later?
- Oh, that one? Sure.
-You in, Taki?
-What? What?! WHAT?!
A café?!
- They've got nice timberwork in here.
- Yeah, it's pretty intricate.
Taki, all set?
Uh...[Gasp]
I could live for a whole month
on what these pancakes cost!
-Uh... maybe a decade ago.
-Hmmm...
Oh, well! It's only a dream!
Dreams are great!
Huh?
Wha? Oh no! I think that I'm late for work.
- You got a shift today?
- Guess you better get goin'.
Right.
Sorry, but uh...
Where exactly do I work?
- Wha?
- Tables six, seven, and ten are waiting!
- Table twelve! Taki!
Got it!
Here you go.
So, the zucchini and tomato
salad with a side of...
- We didn't order that!
- Wha?
- Taki! I told you that
we are out of truffles!
- Taki, you gotta talk louder!
Taki!
When is this nightmare gonna be over?!
Diner: Waiter.
- Hey, you.
- Uh, yes?
See this? Does it look right?
A toothpick's in it.
What would have happened if we ate it?
It's really lucky I noticed when I did.
-Do something.
-Uh... it's just that...
Well, I don't even think
we have toothpicks at this-
What?!
Excuse me. Is everything alright over here?
- Well, like I was trying to tell the guy...
- I'll take care of this.
What's wrong with you today?
We truly apologize.
Your meal is on the house tonight.
Why, thank you.
You weren't hurt, were you?
- Uh... Oku... dera?
- That's "Miss" to you.
-Miss Okudera. About before-
-We just had some bad luck is all.
-No, I- I-
-Those guys were definitely scamming us.
I handled it according to the
manual, but still...
Uh-Ms. Okudera, your skirt!
- Are you alright?
- Did something happen?
Looks like someone cut it.
That guy...
- Do you remember what he looked like?
- No...
- Come with me.
- Hey, Taki.
Okay, take off your skirt.
What?!
N- wh- I'll... I'll look the other way!
Hold on, this won't take long.
All done! Ta-da!
You're really good, Taki!
It's way cuter now!
By the way, I wanted to thank you for
all your help with that customer earlier.
To be honest, well...
I was worried about you.
You aren't that strong,
but you're quick to pick a fight.
I like you better today.
You've got a feminine side.
Who woulda guessed?
"JR Yamanote Line: 7 min."
I gotta say,
this dream sure does seem real.
Ah, looks like he keeps a journal.
So organized.
I wish I lived in Tokyo.
One of her.
Unrequited love?
"Walked to the station with Ms. Okudera
after work, thanks to my feminine powers!"
"Who are you?"
"Mitsuha"
What is this?
Wha?!
What?!
"Thanks to my feminine powers!"
What is going on?!
So, café today?
Thanks, but I gotta go to work.
Ha, do you remember where to go?
Huh?...Ah!
Wait a second. Was that you, Tsukasa? Are you
the one that's been messing with my phone?
Uh... Never mind.
Later.
Well, he's back to normal.
I think he was kinda... cute yesterday.
Uhhhhh....
Uh... what's up?
Don't play dumb.
What about bro code, huh?!
Yeah, you walked home
with her yesterday, right?
Uh, what are you talking about?
Me and Ms. Okudera?
- So what did you guys do?!
Uh, well... I don't remember, actually.
Quit messin' around and tell us!
Okudera, reporting for duty!
-Don't slack off today, you guys.
We're gonna have a good day today.
-Yeah...
Aren't we, Taki?
Hmmm?
"Mitsuha? Who are you?? What are you??"
Yotsuha: I see you're not touching
your boobies today.
Breakfast time! Hurry up!
MY BOOBS?!
Mornin'!
I feel like everyone's
starin' at me for some reason.
- Well you did kinda make a scene yesterday.
- Uh?!
"Still-life drawing"
-Did you see all the election posters?
-Doesn't matter who wins, nothin'll
change, 'cept for who gets the kickback.
-Shhh! Somebody's daddy's dependent on it.
-They're talking about me, right?
Uh... [Nod]
Wait, Mitsuha?!
I... I...
I did what?!
Mitsuha?
"What is this life?"
Could this... could this mean-
-No, no, no, no! Could this mean...
that we're really-
That we're...
in our dreams, that guy and I-
in our dreams, that girl and I-
"Life in Tokyo"
"What is this life?"
- We're switching places?!
At last, hello, you've opened your eyes,
but why won't you even look me in the eyes,
what's wrong with you?
You angrily tell me that I'm late.
Well, I'm sorry, but I did my best
and running at my fastest pace!
Mitsuha: I'm slowly beginning to
realize what's going on.
Taki's in high school and living in Tokyo.
Taki: Two or three times a week, I'll suddenly and randomly
switch with Mitsuha, who's somewhere out in the boonies.
The trigger is sleep. The cause is unknown.
"Condition: Sleep? Cause: Unknown"
Mitsuha: Any memories I have of the switch
get more and more hazy after I wake up.
Taki: But there's no doubt that
we're switching places.
The reactions of everyone
around us prove it.
And that's why...
Mitsuha: That's why we decided to lay out some ground
rules so we could protect each other's way of life.
"Strictly forbidden!"
"No baths! No looking! No touching!"
Things to watch out for during the switches,
and a list of stuff we should never do.
"Don't waste money!
No dialect! Don't be late!"
Taki: We also agreed to leave each other reports
on our phones on the days we switch places...
Mitsuha: So that we can work together to get
through this... weird thing that's happening.
-And yet...
- I cannot believe this guy!
- I cannot believe this girl!
Back in the Zenzenzense 'til this day,
been looking everywhere for you.
I followed the sound of
your innocent laughter,
and it guided me in the right way.
Even if every piece of you disappeared
and if it scattered everywhere...
Mitsuha: Guys will stare. Watch the skirt!
These are basics for a girl!
"Careful with skirts!"
Taki: Stop wasting my money on sweets!
Mitsuha: It's goin' in your body.
Plus, I also worked for that money.
"Braided Cords..."
Taki: Braiding cords is impossible!
Mitsuha: You work way too many shifts!
Taki: 'Cause you keep wasting money!
I wonder if we can push our way through
the countless barrier that's waiting
in the future just beyond our view.
Side-by-side, no way we can lose.
We'll beat destiny at its own game
and make it follow our own rules.
Mitsuha: Had tea with Ms. Okudera on the
way home. You two have a good thing going!
Taki: Quit messing with my
relationships, Mitsuha!
-Hey, Taki... why is a girl
confessing her love to me?
-Maybe you're just more
popular when I'm you.
-You're so full of yourself!
Like you have a girlfriend!
"Don't be so full of yourself!!"
-It's not like you have anyone, either!
- I don't...
"Dummy"
"Idiot"
- Because I don't want a relationship!
I shouldn't for her sake.
Yotsuha: You sure do like your own boobies.
Time to go! Get ready!
Over the course of the last few days, the Tiamat comet
has been visible, but when and where can people see it?
"Comet Tiamat to Reach Perigee"
The Tiamat comet will be moving in the same direction
the sun does: from East to West from our point of view.
Why are you wearin' your uniform?
Yotsuha: Grandma, why does our shrine god's
relic have to be kept so far away?
'Cause of Mayugoro, I don't really know.
- Who's Mayugoro?
- What? He's famous!
Hop on, grandma.
- Oh!
- Watch out! Careful!
Mitsuha. Yotsuha. Do you know about Musubi?
Mu... subi?
It's what we used to call the local guardian
deity long ago, and it means "union".
This word has profound meaning.
Tying strings together is a union, connecting to
people is a union, and the flow of time is a union.
These are all part of the god's power. The
braided cords that we make are tied to that.
A skill from the god,
they represent the flow of time itself.
They assemble and take shape. They twist,
tangle, unravel now and then, break...
and reconnect.
That's what a union is. What time is.
- Have a drink.
- Thanks.
- I want some, too!
- That's also a union.
Whether it's water, rice or sake, when something
becomes a part of a person, it's a union.
It joins their soul, which is why the offering
we're making today is such an important custom.
It connects the god with people.
Hey, I can see it!
This is where it is.
The sacred relic of Miyamizu Shrine.
What lies ahead is the hereafter.
It's the netherworld.
The netherworld!
In order to return to this world, you have to
leave behind what is most important to you.
Like the kuchikamizake.
Kuchikamizake?
You'll offer it at the foot of the shrine
god's relic. After all, it is half of you.
Half... of Mitsuha.
Wow, it's already magic hour!
Magic hour?
- Oh, yeah! Maybe I can see the comet!
- Huh? The comet?
Oh, Mitsuha...
you're dreaming right now, aren't you?
I'm crying? But why?
"I'm almost there. Looking forward to it!"
Ms. Okudera? She's almost where?
Oh, Mitsuha. What did you do?
Date?!
Mitsuha: "Tomorrow's your Tokyo date with Ms.
Okudera."
"Meet up at the station at 10:30!"
Well, that's what I had planned, but...
- Hi, Taki.
- Huh? Agh!
- Wait long?
- Yeah. Aah-no! Uh...
- I just got here.
- Thank goodness. Let's go!
Must be nice.
They've probably met up about now.
Huh?
Why am I...?
Why...?
"It was a date I wanted to go on, but if it so happens that
you end up goin', you better be grateful and enjoy it!"
This is nice! It's my first time here.
So, is this one of your usual go-to spots?
Mitsuha: "At any rate, I bet you've
never even been on a single date."
No way, it's too expensive!
I don't know what to say to her.
"That's why I've handpicked some links
below to help you out, ya wallflower!"
For real?
"You, too, can get a girlfriend!"
"Despite social anxiety, I got a girl!"
"The dos and don'ts of texting!"
She's making fun of me!
"Photo Exhibition: Nostalgia"
You know something, Taki?
Today, you're...
you're like a different person.
Ms. Okudera. You getting hungry?
We could get dinner.
- Uh... let's call it a day.
- U-uh... Alright.
- I could be wrong, and I'm sorry if I am...
- About?
But you used to have a
little crush on me, am I right?
But right now,
there's someone else you like, huh?
- N-n-no! U-uh-it's not that...
- Really?
- There's no one. It's not like that.
- Are you sure about that?
Well, thanks for today. See you at work!
Taki: By the time the date's over,
-you should be able to
see the comet in the sky.
-"...you should be able to
see the comet in the sky."
What does she mean? Weirdo.
-Oh.
Mitsuha: It's you, Teshi.
No. I just didn't feel like
goin', that's all. I'm fine.
What? The festival?
Ah...
Oh yeah, the comet.
It'll be at its brightest today, right?
Okay, got it. Seeya later!
You're just looking forward to seeing
Mitsuha in a yukata, aren'tcha?
I- I am not!
I mean, it didn't even cross my mind.
- Y'know, she sounded kinda down when I talked to her.
- Maybe she just didn't want a call from ya.
It's not funny!
- Sorry to keep ya.
- Oh, she's here!
- You're late!
- [Gasp]
- Mitsuha, what happened to-?
-Your hair!
I guess... it's weird.
You think it's gotta do with some guy.
Like, he broke her heart?
Guys always just assume that
it has to do with a boy.
- She said she felt like cuttin' it.
- Ya sure about that? You really think she
felt like cuttin' off that much of it?
Hey guys, I can see it!
- Whoa, ho-ho!
- Whoa...
- Ah.
Huh?
Phone: "The number you are trying to reach is currently
outside the cellular network or has been turned off due-"
Taki: I'll just have to tell her how lousy
the date ended up the next time we switch.
That's what I thought.
But, for some reason,
the switches Mitsuha and I had
been going through until now...
they never happened again.
"Mountains in Gifu Prefecture"
"Hida Mountains"
Wha-
What are-
What are you doing here?
Okudera: Tsukasa told me about it, so here I am.
I asked for two things: to cover my shift
and to back up my alibi if my dad asked.
Relax, Takagi's gonna take your shift.
Takagi: Gotch'a covered!
But you owe me dinner.
- So, you're all in on it...
- You've got everyone worried about you.
- Huh?
- We can't ignore this! What if somebody's
trying to pull one over on you?
Like catfish?
I mean, you met this person
online, didn't you?
No, not exactly! It's kinda complicated.
- Could be from a dating site-
- She's NOT!
It's because you've been acting awfully
fishy lately, so we're keeping an eye on you.
I don't need a babysitter, okay!
Taki: The switches stopped, my calls never
connected, and texts never went through.
That's why I decided to
go see Mitsuha in person.
I wanted to see her, but...
-What? You don't know where she is exactly?
The town's landscape is your only clue?
Yeah.
And you can't contact her?
What's that about?
-Where are we?
You're a terrible tour guide-
-'Cause I'm not one!
Oh, well. Guess we'll help you search.
- Aww, it's so cute! Look, Taki!
- Seriously, guys?
Okudera: It moved! Awww!
Taki: This is a lost cause.
- What?!
After everything that
we've done for you today?!
You haven't done anything!
- One Takayama Ramen.
I guess I'll have the same.
Sure.
Waitress: Three orders of ramen.
Chef: Got it.
- Think we can make it
back to Tokyo tonight?
- Well, I think we'll be cuttin' it close.
Let me take a look.
- K, thanks.
- Wait, Taki. You sure about that?
Yeah. I kinda feel like maybe I've been
barking up the wrong tree this whole time.
Hey, that's a sketch of Itomori, isn't it?
It's drawn really well.
Come take a look at this, hon!
Yeah, that's Itomori. Takes me back.
My husband was born and raised
there, you know.
Itomori?
Yes, of course! That's the place!
It's nearby, right?
You don't...?
Itomori was...
Itomori...[Gasp]
- But that's where-!
- Wait! Isn't that the
area where that comet-?
Huh?
"Keep Out"
Hey...
Okudera: Is this place really where she's from?
Tsukasa: No way. Taki must have just
confused this with somewhere else.
Taki: No, I didn't.
This was the place.
The schoolyard, these mountains,
even this high school here!
I remember it all!
There's no way you could.
You've gotta know about that
disaster three years ago, right?
- Hundreds of people died.
- They died...
three years ago?
It can't be...
There's no way...
I mean...
I still have the memos she wrote.
They're fading.
Comet Tiamat, with an orbital period
of 1,200 years,
"Itomori, the Town that Vanished"
made a close approach to Earth
three years ago in October.
"Meteor Strikes, Wipes out Town"
Nobody foresaw that its nucleus
would split at its perigee.
"Town Annihilated"
"Over 500 dead or missing"
"Itomori, the Town that Vanished"
A fragment that broke off of it
became a meteor and struck Japan.
"Itomori, comet, damage"
It looks like that day was the
same date as the Autumn Festival.
The point of impact was here.
At 8:42 PM (20:42), it fell right around
where people were gathered for the festival.
"Names of the Victims"
Over 500 died.
It was a third of the town's population,
and now, nobody lives in Itomori anymore.
Teshigawara...
and Sayaka.
"Mitsuha Miyamizu"
That's her?!
You were wrong! You gotta be!
After all,
this girl here died three years ago!
Just... two or three weeks ago,
she said that I'd be able to see the comet.
That means-!
- "You're dreaming right now... aren't you?"
- I...
I...
What...
was I?
Sounds lively over there.
They only have one room left.
I'm really sorry.
It's not a problem.
How's Taki?
He's still reading articles on Itomori.
He's goin' through all those newspapers
and magazines at random. Seems obsessive.
- What is it?
- Oh, sorry. You smoke, huh?
Yeah. I did quit at one point.
What do you think about
what Taki's been saying?
I had feelings for him, y'know.
The way he's been recently.
I mean, he was a nice guy
before, but he's even nicer now.
Kind-of... frantic.
It was cute.
Although, I do think what he's been
telling us is definitely strange-sounding.
But in the end, the fact remains that Taki's met
someone, and that someone is the reason he changed.
That much is for sure.
"Worst-Ever Itomori Comet Disaster"
It was all just a dream.
I recognized the landscape
because I unconsciously remembered
the news from three years ago.
If it's not that, is she... a ghost?
Or...
did I just make it up?
The whole thing?
What was her name?
I can't remember.
Tsukasa said he was gonna
go ahead and take a bath.
Ms. Okudera,
Uh...
I, um...
I realize I've been saying
a lot of strange things.
I'm really sorry, and thank you.
"The Tatara Iron-Making Site"
"The Braided Cords of Itomori"
Braided cords. Pretty.
That band on your wrist.
- That's one, isn't it?
- Hm? Oh.
This thing? Guess so.
Somebody...
Someone gave it to me.
I wear it sometimes as...
kind-of a lucky charm.
Who was it?
- It's late. Why don't you go
down and take a bath, too?
- Sure-wait.
Yeah. Someone who makes these,
they once told me something.
The cords represent the flow of time.
They twist and tangle,
unravel and connect,
and that's what time is.
Maybe if I could-
"Around here?"
Taki...
Distant Voice: Taki.
Taki!
Don't you remember?!
[Gasp]
"I have to go somewhere. Go back to Tokyo
without me. I'll return later. Thanks."
Taki...
Eat this bento up there.
Your drawing of Itomori.
You did a real good job.
-They assemble and take shape,
they twist, tangle,
unravel now and then,
break,
and reconnect.
That's what a union is.
What time is.
There it is.
It's really there!
It wasn't...
a dream.
What lies ahead is the netherworld.
It's still here.
This was Yotsuha's, and this was mine.
This was before the comet.
So when I switched places with her,
it was also three years in the past.
Our times... got tangled somehow.
This is... half of her.
Musubi,
if it's true, and time can be unraveled,
just give me one more chance.
Agh!
[Gasp]
A comet!
ngh! Hh...
[Heartbeat]
- [Crying]
- Your name's going to be...
Mitsuha.
Both of you are my treasures.
You're going to be a big sister!
"Get well soon, Mom!"
I'm so sorry, my dears...
Dad, when is mommy coming home?
- I couldn't help her!
- Get ahold of yourself!
- Who cares about the shrine?!
- But you're in charge now!
- I loved Futaba, not Miyamizu Shrine!
- Get out!
Now listen to me, girls.
Starting today,
you'll be living with grandma.
"Who are you?"
"Who am I?" Who are you?
"Mitsuha"
"Idiot"
Don't be full of yourself!
Like you have a girlfriend!
Must be nice.
They've probably met up about now.
Why am I...?
- I'm going to Tokyo.
- What?! Wait, Sis!
Grandma?
Would you mind doing me a favor?
Oh yeah, the comet.
It'll be at its brightest today, right?
-Mitsuha, don't go there!
Mitsuha!
You've gotta get out of town
before the comet strikes!
[Gasp]
Mitsuha, run!
Mitsuha! Mitsuha! Mitsuha!
[Gasp]
Taki (as Mitsuha): Mitsuha.
She's alive!
[Sobbing]
Let me guess, you're touching your boo-
[Gasp]
[Crying] Her sister!
Yotsuha!
Yotsuha: Ungh!
[Shudder]
I think she's finally lost it.
Just for today,
I-I'm gonna head out first...
She's lost it...
Really lost it...
Totally!
Totally...
-For all you stargazers out there, the comet Tiamat
has been visible to the naked eye for about a week now.
Tonight, it will finally reach its perigee around 7:40 PM (19:40),
and be at its maximum brightness when viewed from the Earth's...
It's tonight! There's still time left!
Mornin', Mitsuha!
What's this?
Hold on...
- You're not Mitsuha, are you?
- W-wait, how did you-?
You already knew?
No, but watching the way you've been
behaving lately stirred some memories up.
When I was a young girl,
I had some pretty strange dreams myself.
Huh?
Though it's been so long, the memories of who I became
in those dreams have pretty much faded at this point.
Faded?
Treasure the experience.
Dreams eventually will fade away.
I went through similar times myself,
and so did your mother.
What if...
all those dreams that
the Miyamizu people had!
It had to do with today!
Grandma, you have to listen to me!
Tonight,
the comet is going to fall on Itomori!
- You're all gonna die!
- Huh?
"Nobody's gonna believe that?"
I didn't expect that out
of Mitsuha's grandma.
It doesn't matter!
There's no way I'm gonna let them all die!
Mitsuha!
What happened... to-?
What'd you-?
Your hair!
-Ugh, the haircut?
Looked better before, huh?
-No, i-i-it's good!
Nevermind that! If we don't do
something about tonight, we'll all die!
It's up to us to save everyone!
Wait, shouldn't you be in school?
Well, we sort-of have to save the
town, or something.
Heh?
- The warning system?
- Yeah, those speakers all over the town.
"Superimposition, frequency"
I get it. It could work!
- Niiiice job, Teshi.
- Hey, I don't think you should
be sittin' so close to me.
- What's wrong. Uh-oh! You shyyy?
- Would you quit it?!
It ain't proper and you know it!
"Club Discontinued - Keep Out"
Taki (as Mitsuha): T-hahahahaha!
Such a gentleman.
I bought all the snacks, guys.
- Here's the change.
- Sorry for the trouble.
I didn't mind.
- We oughta be gettin' paid.
- Quit complaining.
So? Wha'dcha come up with?
Got an evacuation plan?
A- A-
A BOMB?!
Yeah, we have water gel explosives we
use for construction at our storage site.
AND the warning system?
Our startup frequency can hijack the
town's warning system pretty easily,
so we can broadcast an evacuation warning
for the whole town right from school!
Look, we're outside the disaster area here,
so we'll just make an announcement
to evacuate to the school.
It's-
- It's totally a crime!
- You'll be in charge
of the broadcast, Saya.
- Why me?!
- You're in the Broadcast Club.
- And I'll be in charge of the explosives.
- While I go have a word with the mayor.
- Why?
- 'Cause if the evacuation order's not comin' from Town Hall, then nobody's gonna go anyway.
But if I talk to the mayor,
as his daughter, I can convince him.
It's the perfect plan!
Fine, I don't really care
one way or the other.
This is just a theory of yours, right?
Well...
Theories can be based on reality. Like, do you know the
story of how Itomori Lake was formed? It's a crater!
"A meteor crater lake
formed 1,200 years ago."
- That means a meteor hit this area
at least once a thousand years ago!
- Right. That's why-!
Nice one, Teshi!
- Let's go evacuate the town!
Mitsuha's Father: What on earth
are you talking about?!
Like I said,
-We have to evacuate everyone
in town before tonight or else-
-Enough! Shut up!
"The comet's going to split
in two and strike the town?"
"Itomori Town Hall"
"Over 500 will die?"
How dare you stand there
and spout such nonsense!
If you're serious, you must be sick!
I guess recklessness is a Miyamizu trait.
I'll have a car take you to the
city hospital for an examination.
We will continue this discussion
after you've seen a doctor.
You!
You son of a- !
Mitsuha's Father: Mitsuha...
No...
Wait a minute...
Who are you?
-I'll see you guys at the festival, ba-bye!
-We'll meet ya at the step stone shrine.
Don't be late, k?
- Ba-bye!
- Seeya!
- Later!
You shouldn't go!
-You've got to leave town!
Tell all of your friends!
-What's wrong with you?!
- Mitsuha!
- What was that about?
- Come on, let's go.
What are you doing, huh?
If it was Mitsuha,
would she have been able to convince him?
- Is all this my fault?!
- Huh?!
Yotsuha, promise me that you'll
leave town with grandma before dark!
What?!
- You're gonna die if you stay here!
- What are you talking about?!
And why did you suddenly go to Tokyo yesterday?!
You've been acting really strange lately!
- Went to Tokyo?
- Hey! Mitsuha!
How'd it go with your old man?
Hey, Mitsuha!
What's with your sister?
Don't know.
[Ding]
Could she be over there?
What's that? What's over there?
- Let me use your bike, Teshi.
- Hey.
Mitsuha.
And what do we do?
Get things ready like we planned!
I'm counting on you!
Mitsuha: Oh my gosh! I'm Taki again!
What's Taki doin' out here?
The town!
It's gone!
So...
does that mean...
I... died?!
"Taki."
"Taki!"
"Don't you remember?!"
I'm going to Tokyo for a few hours.
Wha? Right now?
- But why?
- Uh...
For a date.
- You have a boyfriend in Tokyo?!
- I-I didn't say it was a date for me.
"I'll be back tonight."
Mitsuha: If I suddenly show up, will it
be a nuisance or a surprise?
He might not like it if I do.
"The number you are trying to reach
is currently outside the cellular network."
I guess it won't happen, but...
What if it did?
What would I do?
Would I annoy him?
"Tiamat Makes
Closest Approach Tomorrow"
Would it be awkward, or maybe...
he'd be glad to see me.
"The number you are trying to reach
is currently outside the cellular network."
I guess we won't meet.
But... there's one thing I'm certain of.
If we see each other,
We'll definitely know right away...
that you were the one who was in me,
and that I was the one who was in...
- you.
- Sorry!
[Gasp]
'Scuse me.
Taki: Agh!
That time...
three years ago.
Before I even knew you...
Mitsuha: [Whispering] Taki...
Taki?
- Taki!
- Huh?
Uh... It's me!
- Don't you... remember?
- Uh...
Sorry, who are you?
I- I'm sorry.
Ah!
Mitsuha: But, he's Taki!
Taki: What a weird girl.
Train announcer: "Yotsuya. Yotsuya.
Stay clear of the doors."
- Hold on!
- Huh?
- Egh!
- What's your name?
Mitsuha!
My name is...
"Mitsuha!"
Taki (as Mitsuha): Three years ago...
you showed up.
It was... to see me!
Mitsuha (as Taki): Taki.
[Echoing] Mitsuha!
Taki?
Mitsuha!
You're here, right?
Inside my body?
Taki?!
Taki, where are you?!
Taki (as Mitsuha): That was Mitsuha.
I can hear her voice, but...
Taki, where are you?
Taki!!
[Ding]
- Uh!
- Huh?
Mitsuha (as Taki): Taki, are you...?
Taki (as Mitsuha)i: Are you there?
- Magic hour.
[Gasp]
Uh...
Taki: Mitsuha.
Mitsuha: Taki.
Taki!
[Sobbing] You're really here!
- Taki!
- I came all this way to see you,
which wasn't easy...
since you were pretty far away.
How is that even...?
Because, back then!
Well, I drank some of your kuchikamizake.
Huh?
Oh...
You... you drank that?!
Huh?
- STUPID PERVERT!
- Wha-WHA?!
Mitsuha: Yeah, that's right! You were
touching my boobies, WEREN'T YOU?!
Taki: WHA- ?!
- Wha-ho-how do you even- ?!
- 'Cause Yotsuha saw you!
I just-I couldn't help myself!
- But it was just the one time!
- "Just the one time?"
How many times is it the issue?!
Sorry!
Wait...
Is that...?
Oh.
Yeah, it's yours,
but you visited before I knew you.
So, I didn't know who you were.
Here.
I kept it for three years,
but I think it's time you got it back.
- Whaddya think?
- Oh, uh, well...
- it's not bad.
- Oh, you're lyin'!
Busted!
Why you gotta be like that?
- [Laughing]
Hey, Mitsuha.
You still have a lot to do.
Listen.
- It's coming.
- Don't worry.
- You still have enough time.
- [Nod]
I'll do my best.
It looks like magic hour is almost...
over.
Hey, Mitsuha.
Just so we don't forget
things when we wake up...
Let's write down our names.
Here.
Mitsuha.
Hey.
Mitsuha?
I was planning to tell you...
that wherever you are in the world,
I swear that I'll find you
again, no matter what.
Your name...
is Mitsuha.
It'll be okay!
I'll remember!
Mitsuha.
Mitsuha!
Your name is Mitsuha!
Your name is-!
Who...
are you?
And what...
did I even come here for?
I came...
I came all this way to see her!
I came to save her!
I wanted her to be alive!
Who was it again?
Who?
Who did I come to see?
Someone precious!
Someone I don't wanna forget!
Someone I shouldn't!
Who was it?
Who was it?!
Who?!
What's your name?!
Mitsuha: Taki.
Taki.
It'll be fine!
I remember!
I'll never forget!
Taki.
Your name is...
Taki!
"Itomori Substation"
Teshi!
Mitsuha!
- Where the heck have you been?
- He said sorry for breakin' your bike.
Wha? Who did?
I did!
You're gonna have to
explain it to me later.
That thing is gonna fall, right?
- For real?
- For real. I saw it with my own eyes.
What? You did, huh?
Well, I guess it's settled, then.
We're both officially criminals.
"Broadcasting Room"
What?! Do I really have to...?!
Once the town's power goes out, the emergency
generator should kick in right away.
Use the broadcast equipment once it does.
Don't be scared, Saya!
And repeat it as many times as you can!
Woo-hoo!
- You can do it!
- Aw, nuts! It's do or die!
- Shouldn't it be goin' off?
- Hell if I know!
- Oooh...
- Ha ha!
- What was that?
- It was pretty loud, too.
Look over there!
- Hey look, up there!
- Whoa!
This is Itomori Town Hall!
- Reports of an explosion at
the substation are coming in!
- An explosion? Did I hear that right?
Wildfires are possible,
as well as the threat of more explosions!
Residents in the followin' areas, please
evacuate to Itomori High School immediately.
Kadoiri District.
- Sakagami District!
- Honey, we should go.
The broadcast isn't coming from us?
Well, who the hell is it, then?
Miyamori District.
Oyazawa District.
Let's go, Mitsuha!
Teshi!
- Everyone, run! There's a wildfire!
- Wildfire, please run!
- Get outta here! Run, there's a fire!
- It's not safe here! Please, evacuate!
It's not workin',
we're runnin' out of time!
- Mitsuha!
- [Sobbing]
What's wrong?
What is it...?
I can't remember what his name is anymore!
What is with you?!
You're the one who started all of this!
We can't evacuate everyone
without firefighters!
Get goin'! You gotta convince your old man!
Everybody, get to the high school! HURRY!
Oh, it's Mitsuha.
-Why would terrorists attack way out here?
What is Chubu Electric saying?
-They're still checking.
Any update? No wildfires yet?
You sure? Got it.
Make them stop this broadcast immediately!
Haven't you located its source yet?
Mayor, the Takayama sensor
station just called!
From the high school?
Once again, residents in the following
areas, please evacuate to Itomori High...
- Ah!
- What are you doing?! Turn that off!
- They got Saya!
- Oh no.
What were you thinking, Natori?! I swear!
This is Itomori Town Hall.
We are currently confirming
the reports of the accident.
- We instruct all residents to remain calm and stay where they are until further notice.
- I guess... we have to stay put?
- What is goin' on?
- So stay on standby.
Come on! They said everyone should evacuate!
The high school's the evacuation center!
-Katsuhiko!
Tell me...
What do you think you're doing?!
Sorry, Mitsuha.
This is the end.
[Gasp]
Oh, my God!
It's actually splittin' apart!
Look at that! The comet has split into two large
parts and meteors are now falling to Earth!
- Uh, I don't believe anyone
could have predicted this.
- Either way, we have
quite the mystical view here.
-So, what does the comet's
nucleus splitting mean for us?
-The comet's not within the Roche limit, so the nucleus
itself must've had a structural weakness for this to happen.
-Comet Shoemaker-Levy 9 broke apart
and collided with Jupiter in 1994.
- There were at least 21 fragments...
- I'm going outside to take a look.
- The fragments will likely burn up
well before reaching the ground.
- Does it pose a danger?
-Probability of a meteor actually landing
on a populated area is quite small.
-never foresaw this development.
- To predict the trajectory...
- As we stand here witnessing
this spectacle,
unassisted...
and with our bare eyes,
it strikes me that living in such an age
has never felt more fortunate than now.
Mitsuha: Hey...
Who...
are you?
Who?
Who is he?
Someone precious.
Someone I shouldn't forget!
Someone I didn't want to!
Who?
Who?!
Who are you?!
What's your name?!
Oh no!
Ah! Argh!
Ungh!
-"So that we don't forget
things when we wake up..."
"Let's write down our names."
"I love you"
Writing this...
doesn't help!
I won't know your name...
[Crying]
Dad!
- Mitsuha.
- There you are!
Don't tell me you're back!
Ah...
-"It was almost like seeing
something out of a dream."
"Nothing more or less..."
"than a breathtaking view."
Words like "tomorrow"
or "future" or "fate",
no matter how far they extend their hands,
we breathe, we dream, we raise our love
in a timeless land
that is far out of reach.
Even the second, hour hands of the clock.
They look at us sideways
as they tick and tock.
How I hope to have
forever to spend this life,
no- all future lives
right here in this world with you!
Taki: Huh?
Why am I here?
What am I... doing?
[Gasp]
U-uh!
Train Announcer: "The doors are closing.
Please be careful."
Taki: I'm always searching for something.
This... feeling has consumed me...
for some time.
The reason I applied for this position-
The landscapes people live in-
To build a city's landscape-
Even Tokyo. It might vanish too one day.
And so, I wanna make landscapes
that- how should I put this?
That can continue to warm peoples' hearts.
[Sigh]
Takagi: That bad? How many does that make it?
Taki: I've stopped counting.
Tsukasa: Doesn't sound too promising.
- Who asked you?
- That suit could be the problem.
-It looks just like yours!
- Well, I have two offers.
- I have eight myself.
"LINE: You have a new message."
Taki: Is what I'm searching for...
someone?
Or somewhere?
Or am I just searching
for the right job?
I don't even really know.
Oh!
- You're job hunting, huh?
- I haven't had much luck, though.
- Hey, maybe it's the suit
that's killing your chances.
- Uh-does it really look that bad on me?
-So, why the sudden call today?
-I was in the area for work and I figured
it had been a while since I saw your face.
"8 years since the comet disaster"
Okudera: Remember that one time when we
went all the way to Itomori?
You were still in high school back
then, so it was...
- Heh. Five years ago.
- That long?
It seems like...
I've forgotten a lot.
Taki: I don't... remember all that much,
either.
About back then.
Maybe we argued.
She and Tsukasa went
back to Tokyo without me.
I spent the night alone on some mountain.
That's about all I remember.
But, at one point in time, I found myself strangely
drawn to the incident involving that comet.
A fragment of the comet destroyed
a town in that disaster,
"Evacuation of residents to
high school grounds confirmed."
but, miraculously,
most of the people living
in the town were unhurt.
The town happened to be holding
an emergency drill that day,
"No deaths, 104 wounded"
"An unprecedented natural disaster"
and most of its residents
were outside the impact zone.
"Residents safe"
"Disaster Foretold?"
The sheer luck and coincidence of it
all sparked various conspiracy theories.
"Mayor Miyamizu's hidden agenda"
I read a lot articles about it back then.
"Mysterious explosion at the substation"
I was kind-of obsessed.
But whatever the reason I had for my
interest... is a mystery to me now.
I didn't even know anybody in that town.
Thanks for today. This is far enough.
I do hope,
that at some point,
you'll find happiness, too.
I feel like I'm always searching.
For something.
Someone.
"Construction company job interview"
I feel like I do wanna go
to one more bridal fair.
They're all the same!
- A Shinto weddin' sure sounds nice, too!
- You said you wanted to
be married in a chapel!
- Oh, that reminds me, Teshi!
- Uh!
Would ya please shave before the ceremony?
I'm goin' on a diet for it, you know.
She says as she's eatin' a cake!
- I'll get serious tomorrow.
- Uh...
[Ding]
[Gasp]
[Sigh]
"Itomori, the Town that Vanished"
"October 4, 2013 - Itomori Vanished"
"Kadoiri Bridge"
"Itomori Elementary School"
"Miyamizu Shrine"
Taki: The landscape of a town
that's no longer there.
Why does looking at it make
my chest feel so tight?
Now, just a little more,
only just a little more.
Let's stay here a little longer now.
Just a little more,
only just a little more.
Let's stick together
just a little bit longer.
Just a little more,
only just a little more.
Let's stay here a little longer now.
Now just a little more,
only just a little more.
Let's stick together
just a little bit longer.
Taki: I was always searching...
Mitsuha: Searching for...
-someone!
Oh yes, we are time fliers,
scaling the walls of time. Climber
tired of playing
hide-and-seek with time and
always comin' dead short.
I'll never let you go now,
promise I will never let you go now,
'cause my hand finally has reached yours!
Why should I have to?
Oh, you're sure quite a showy crier.
Wanna stop your tears,
see your eyes drier.
But when I went to wipe your tears dry,
you refused, but I saw them
pouring down your face, I knew why.
Crying even when you're happy,
smiling even when you're feeling lonely.
It's because a part of you
has made it here before the rest has.
Taki: Excuse me!
Haven't we...?
Have I...
met you somewhere?
Mitsuha: I thought so, too!
- Can I ask you...
- your name?
The sorrowful gust of wind that
blew right between you and me,
where did it find the loneliness
it carried on the breeze?
Looking up at the sky after
shedding a stream of tears,
I could see for miles of blue,
it's never been so clear.
Speeches that my father gave me
would always make me despair.
Somehow, I feel a warmth and comfort today.
Your ever kind heart, the way you smile,
and even how you find your dreams.
I knew nothing, so honestly,
I've always copied you.
Now, just a little more,
only just a little more.
Let's stay here a little longer now.
Now just a little more,
only just a little more.
Let's stick together
just a little bit longer.
Oh yes, we are time fliers
scaling the walls of time. Climber
tired of playing hide-and-seek
with time and
always comin' dead short.
Crying even when you're happy,
smiling even when you're feeling lonely.
It's because a part of you has
made it here before the rest has.
I used to wish upon the stars,
the toys that I once adored.
Forgotten now, are rollin'
'round the corners of the floor.
Finally, my dream has counted
up to a hundred today.
Someday, I'll trade them
all for just the very one.
Girl that I have seen in school,
that never have told "hello",
After class today, I waved and
said, “See you tomorrow!”
It's not really that bad trying
something new every once in a while,
especially if I can do
it with you by my side.
Now just a little more,
only just a little more.
Let's stay here a little longer now.
Just a little more,
only just a little more.
Let's stick together
just a little bit longer.
Oh yes, we are time fliers, so, and I...
I knew who you were way before...
way before I even knew my own name.
There's no clue, but I'm sure. I swear!
Even if you're not around
in this wide world,
of course it surely would
have some kind of meaning.
But if when you're not
around in this crazy world,
would be like the month of
August without summer break.
And if you're not around
in this great world,
would be like Santa Claus without any glee.
If you're not around in this wide world!
Oh yes, we are time fliers
scaling the walls of time. Climber
tired of playing hide-and-seek
with time and
always comin' dead short.
No, never mind that!
No, never mind what I said now,
'cause I'm on my way to you!
Oh, we are time fliers,
dashing up the steps of time now!
No more playing hide-and-seek
with you and time
and always comin' dead short!
You're quite a showy crier!
Wanna stop your tears,
see your eyes drier!
But when I went to wipe your tears dry,
you refused but I saw them pouring
down your face, I knew why!
Crying even when I'm happy,
smiling even when I'm feeling lonely!
It's because the heart of mine
has made it here before my body.